SUDHEERA

Mobile: 9900800327

Email: sudheera.njs@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Web developer and web product manager with 3+ years of experience developing complex web based application and e-commerce websites. Posses strong technical skills and ability to lead software development teams. Strong understanding of the internet space. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Adobe Photoshop, python, SQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2014 - Present:

Web Developer | Product Manager, ibibo Group, Bangalore

Description: goibibo is the largest online hotels booking engine in India and also one of the leading air aggregator. goibibo is also the number one ranked mobile app under the travel category. goibibo is part of the ibibo Group that also owns India's No. 1 online Bus ticketing platform, redBus.in and recently launched car pooling app, "ibibo Ryde".

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Execute user interface designs from product requirements and UI specification.
- Translate wireframes and prototypes into production-quality templates.
- Continuously explores new web design techniques, tools, and technologies.
- Analyzing and Optimizing websites to make them more search engine friendly.
- Working closely with design, engineering, operations, data science, marketing and sales teams and seek their input on key product decisions.
- Develop new products/features and seek to refine existing features by conducting user research, analysing usage patterns etc.
- Manage the product development process from conception through design, development, release, analysis and iteration.
- Contributing to the overall product roadmap across all platforms (web, mobile) keeping in mind the shortterm, medium-term and long-term interests of the company.

October 2012 - April 2014:

Web Developer, Lore Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore

Client: Perfect Market .com (Taboola.com)

Project Title: Digital Publishing Suite, Perfect Market Enterprise

Role: Development

SUDHEERA

- Perfect Market, Inc. is the leading provider of digital publishing software solutions for driving traffic, engagement and revenue. Digital Publishing Suite, a comprehensive set of tools that address content recirculation, social discovery, search engine optimization, on-site promotions and ad optimization.
- Developed new features and functionality especially related to client browser-side capabilities including JavaScript, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, Responsive web design, Media queries, Cross browser compatible and Search engine optimization.
- Responsible for interaction design, UI architecture and framework definition and product usability.
- Converted Photoshop designs into a working website features using Web standards.
- Implemented Google, Yahoo, Rich Media, Group-on, standard, Ads implementation for client sites and other modules like linkbox, featured-articles and related-articles.

Aug 2011 - October 2012:

Software Developer - Intern, picomize, New York/ Bangalore

- Picomize (<u>www.picomize.com</u>) makes it simple for picture professionals to find the right image for their campaign by enabling them to work directly with Picomize photographers who learn and adapt to their photo needs.
- As a member of the core team, I have been involved in the development of the entire site. In my capacity as a developer I have worked on backend development of the site on Django platform using Python. I have also worked on the front end of the site using HTML, CSS, Javascripts, J Query and Ajax

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, Jquery *Framework:* Django, Twitter Bootstrap, Less (Intermediate level)

Language: Python (Intermediate level)

Operating Systems: GNU Linux-(Ubuntu 14.10)

IDE: Eclipse, Pycharm, Sublime, Vim

Database Management: Mysql (Intermediate level)

Familiar server environments: AWS

Specialties: UI Development, Product Management, Agile Software Development, SEO, Information Management, Team Building, Leadership.

EDUCATION

Vishveshwaraya Technological University, Karnataka, India

2007-11

Bachelors in Engineering, Information Science

First Class

SUDHEERA

Viveka Pre-University College, Kota, Karnataka, India 11th and 12th Grade

2005-07

Second Class

Viveka High School, Kota, Karnataka, India 10th Grade 2004-05

First Class

OTHER HEIGHTS OF LIFE AND EXPERIENCES

- Developed and **co-founded** a "Humour" sharing platform www.dozoff.com Used an open source python stack in the Backend and Frontend using JavaScript, Jquery, HTML, CSS. Dozoff is a community for fun which is open for all. With the intention to make everyone laugh everyday, we have taken the first step to create a platform where anyone can share their funny images or memes with the entire world. With that said, no more closed groups and no more feeling lonely as Dozoff is gonna be your "Stress buster".
- Co-founded and running Question and Answer Community for sports enthusiast. thenextsports.com Initially TNS was developed as a resume builder using an open stack which eventually turned into a Q and A site for which numbers are small but visits are coming from over 50 countries. TNS taught us about key factors of SEO and Google's way of indexing content. TNS hosted on AWS EC2.
- Have attended various hackathon and start-up event likes IN50HRS, Unpluggd, Stack overflow and TechCrunch Hackathon Bangalore.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct to my knowledge and I bear that responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Sudheera